prosper.com 2018-12-25

# Privacy Policy | Prosper

Important Privacy Choices

Welcome to Prosper. We believe that consumers deserve the utmost respect when it comes to the privacy of their personal information. This Privacy Policy applies to Prosper Marketplace, Inc. and its wholly owned subsidiary, Prosper Funding LLC (together, “Prosper”, “we,” “us” or “our.”).

We have prepared this Privacy Policy to explain how we collect, use, protect, and disclose information and data when you use Prosper’s websites, services, and mobile applications. This Privacy Policy also explains your choices for managing information preferences, including opting out of certain uses of your personal information. By accessing or using Prosper’s site or services, you consent to this Privacy Policy.

If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, or if you need assistance in exercising any of your choices under this policy, please contact us at [privacy@prosper.com](mailto:privacy@prosper.com).

This policy applies to all current and former Prosper customers. Note that, in order to use our services, you must be 18 years of age or older.

**INFORMATION PROSPER COLLECTS ABOUT YOU**

**Information Provided by You**

We collect personal information about you that you provide while you use [www.prosper.com](http://www.prosper.com/) or [www.prosperhealthcare.com](http://www.prosperhealthcare.com/) or any associated websites, desktop or mobile applications. We collect most of this information during the registration and/or application process for borrowers and investors. Additional information may be gathered during your subsequent use of the site, or when we communicate with you via telephone, email or other means.

Certain personal information must be supplied during the investor and/or borrower registration and application processes in order to meet our legal obligations, verify your identity, determine eligibility for credit, protect against fraud, and complete your transaction. The following categories of information may be collected:

  * Your basic identifying information (for example, your name, address, email, telephone number, and date of birth);
  * Your Social Security number;
  * Your employment and income information;
  * Your bank account information;
  * For a loan to be used with a merchant or service provider (e.g., a healthcare provider) the identity of the merchant or service provider and the name of the party that will receive the good or service;
  * Other information you may provide in connection with a financial product or service, such as your demographic information (where permitted or required by applicable law) and the location and value of the property securing your loan;
  * Any personal information you provide us.

In addition, we gather names, email addresses and phone numbers of people who contact us with questions. We collect this information only for the purpose of responding to inquiries. If you use our “refer-a-friend” feature, we will collect information from you in order to process your referral request.

If you use the comments section of our blog on [www.prosper.com](http://www.prosper.com/), you should be aware that information you submit is stored there and will be visible to other users of the website.

**Information Collected From Third Parties**

When you check your rate or apply for a loan through Prosper, we will collect information from credit bureaus and other third parties to determine your eligibility for credit, perform analysis, provide you with marketing offers and assess risks related to your potential loan and, if you are a personal loan applicant, to help investors determine whether to commit to your personal loan. If you obtain a personal loan through Prosper, we also collect information throughout the life of your personal loan through Prosper from credit bureaus and other third parties in order to assess risks associated with your personal loan and provide information to investors interested in buying or selling your personal loan, and to provide you with marketing offers. If another company refers you to Prosper or assists you in any way in the application process, we may also collect your information from that company in order to process your application.

The following categories of information are generally collected for loan applicants and borrowers:

  * Your identifying and application information (for example, your name, address, email, telephone number, date of birth, social security number, and employment information);
  * Your credit score, credit history and other information related to your creditworthiness, identity and financial transactions;
  * Your bank account information and recent transactions;
  * If you applied for a loan to be used with a merchant or service provider, information related to any dispute you submit regarding the merchant or service provider;
  * If you applied for a loan through the Prosper Healthcare Lending program that is processed through an online finance platform other than Prosper, the status and terms of your loan or loan offer through that platform;
  * If you applied for a home equity line of credit (HELOC) through Prosper, information related to your demographics (as required by law) and property, and any other information to evaluate and complete your application.

If you register as an investor through Prosper, we will collect information from credit bureaus and other third parties to verify your identity and bank account information and assess risks related to your account.  If another company refers you to Prosper or assists you in any way in the registration or investing process, we may also collect your information from that company in order to process your registration or request, or to update your account information.

**Information Gathered Based on Your Activity on the Prosper Platform**

In order to provide services to you, improve our business and maintain records required by law, Prosper collects information about your transactions and activity. For personal loan borrowers, this includes your payment history. For investors, this includes your fund transfers and purchases. For all users, Prosper collects information about your computer and your visits to [www.prosper.com](http://www.prosper.com/) or [www.prosperhealthcare.com](http://www.prosperhealthcare.com/) and other Prosper websites, such as your IP address, geographical location, browser type, referral source, length of visit, button clicks and page views.

**_Tracking Technologies_**

Cookies and Web Beacons. Prosper and our marketing partners and service providers use technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts, to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports on this activity on an individual and aggregated basis.

We use cookies when you interact with our websites to keep track of your personal session, help authenticate your account, and detect fraud. Cookies are also used to gather statistical data, such as which pages are frequently visited, what is downloaded, and the address of sites visited immediately before or after coming to our site. You can control the use of cookies within your web browser. However, if you reject cookies, your ability to use some features or areas of our websites may be limited.

Usage Data & Site Activity. Prosper also uses Local Storage, such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5.

Third Party Technologies. We also partner with third parties to manage our advertising on other sites and evaluate our overall site performance. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on our websites and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests or help us track the success of our marketing efforts or overall site performance. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out of certain advertising networks by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

**_Do-Not-Track Signals_**

Prosper does not process or respond to “do not track” signals or other similar signals whereby a visitor to a website requests that it disable collection of information about the visitor’s online activities over time and across different websites.

**HOW PROSPER USES YOUR INFORMATION**

**Processing Your Transaction**

If you register as a borrower and/or apply for a loan, Prosper will use your information to facilitate your loan or loan request. This may include:

  * Generating your borrower profile, processing your loan application and verifying your identity and application information;
  * Assigning you a Prosper Rating;
  * Enabling automatic payments and fund transfers with other financial institutions;
  * Implementing collection activities as needed;
  * Communicating with you concerning your loan application, Prosper account, and/or transactions;
  * Addressing any disputes you may raise.

If you register as an individual investor, Prosper will use your information to facilitate marketplace investing. This may include:

  * Generating your investor profile;
  * Enabling automatic payments and fund transfers with other financial institutions;
  * Communicating with you concerning your Prosper account and transactions;
  * Addressing any disputes you may raise concerning your account.

**Analysis & Data Optimization**

Prosper also uses your information to conduct analyses related to our services and our websites. We use this information to improve our services and credit model. We also use this information to improve our websites’ usability and to evaluate the success of particular marketing campaigns and other activities.

**Marketing & Surveys**

Prosper may also use your personal information to select you for certain marketing offers, newsletters, surveys and/or requests for feedback regarding your experience. Prosper may use your personal information both to select you for an offer and to communicate that offer to you.

**_Optional Marketing Communications_**

**Receipt of marketing communications via email is voluntary. If you do not wish to receive these communications, you may sign into your[Prosper Account](https://www.prosper.com/signin), select “Settings” from the drop down menu, and disable communication types you no longer wish to receive in the section titled “Communication Preferences.” You may also contact us at [privacy@prosper.com](mailto:privacy@prosper.com) and we will assist you in disabling optional communications**.

**HOW PROSPER SHARES YOUR INFORMATION**

We will share your personal information with nonaffiliates (companies not related by common ownership or control) and among affiliates (companies related by common ownership or control, including but not limited to the companies covered by this policy) only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. By law, you are permitted to limit some types of sharing, but not others.

Prosper shares your information with third parties as permitted by law, including in the following specific ways:

  * Originating Banks. All loans originated through Prosper are made by a third party bank that may extend credit to you (“originating bank”). If you apply for a loan through Prosper, you are also providing your information to the potential originating bank, and further information may be provided to that bank after your loan originates. The use of your information by your originating bank is governed by that bank’s privacy policy.

  * Third Party Financing Platforms. Certain loan applications through Prosper Healthcare Lending may also be processed by another online finance platform, to which you are providing your information when you apply for a loan. The use of your information by that online financing platform is governed by that company’s privacy policy.

  * Third Party Service Providers. Prosper relies on third party service providers to help us conduct our business and marketing activities, such as maintaining our files and records, offering customer service, sending marketing communications, or facilitating fund transfers. Prosper may share your information with such companies, which are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to Prosper. Information may also be shared among affiliates (including but not limited to the companies covered by this policy) for this purpose where one affiliated company provides services to or on behalf of another affiliated company in connection with your account or application.

  * Potential Purchasers of Personal Loan. Prosper shares your information, including your Prosper Borrower Rating, on an anonymous basis to allow potential purchasers to decide whether to commit to your personal loan. This information is also contained anonymously in personal loan data files available through Prosper’s Developer Tools and Marketplace Performance pages. Although your credit information is displayed, your identity is never shared with investors until your personal loan has been purchased.

  * Purchasers of Personal Loan. If Prosper sells your personal loan originated through our platform, we may provide the purchaser of your personal loan with your personal and credit information. Information is only released to personal loan purchasers that are qualified financial institutions with adequate protections to safeguard your personal information. Information provided to investors in connection with sales of our fractional Borrower Payment Dependent Notes (“Notes”) will not include personal identifying information. For more information on Notes, please see our [Prospectus](https://www.prosper.com/prospectus).

  * Referral Partners. If you were referred to Prosper by another company (a “Referral Partner”) or person, Prosper will share your information as necessary to honor the terms of its agreement with that Referral Partner or person and to process your transaction. In some cases Prosper may share with a Referral Partner for that Referral Partner’s own business purposes, such as to analyze and improve its business and provide targeted marketing offers to you. Your rights with respect to this sharing are discussed in the following section.

  * Merchants or Service Providers. If you applied for a loan to be used with a merchant or service provider, Prosper may share your information with the merchant or service provider associated with your loan application.

  * Credit Bureaus. Prosper may share your personal information with credit bureaus to meet our credit reporting obligations.

  * Affiliates. Prosper affiliates, including entities covered by this policy and other companies related by common ownership or control may share your information with each other, including information related to your creditworthiness, for purposes of general business analysis or to present targeted marketing offers to you or others. Your rights with respect to this sharing are discussed in the following section.

  * Legal Requests & Regulatory Requirements. Prosper may also share information to comply with, or to allow investors or potential investors to comply with, any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request; or for the purposes of limiting fraud; or in connection with an audit or the sale of Prosper to a third party.

  * Sharing of Anonymized Data. Prosper may share aggregated and anonymized data sets including your information with third parties, including but not limited to business partners, service providers, loan purchasers, potential loan purchasers, and among Prosper affiliates. No personally identifiable information will be included in these data sets.

* * *

**IMPORTANT PRIVACY CHOICES**

**_Consent to information sharing with third party companies (Referral Partners)_** **:** By accepting this privacy policy, you agree that Prosper may immediately begin sharing your information with any third party company that referred you to Prosper so that that company may use your information for their own business purposes, including to market to you. For example, if you were referred to Prosper by another company through a website link or telephone transfer, Prosper may share some of your information, such as the existence and terms of your loan, with that company. You may revoke this consent at any time by following the procedures outlined below. If you revoke consent we will not subsequently share your information with these companies except as necessary to complete the transaction you initiated.

**_Right to restrict information sharing with companies we own or control (affiliates)_** **:** Prosper may share your information among affiliated companies whether or not those companies are covered by this policy. Federal law gives you the right to limit this sharing where it includes information about your creditworthiness other than your transactions and experiences with Prosper or is used for the purpose of marketing to you. If you would like to opt-out of this type of sharing, please follow the instructions below. We may begin sharing your information related to your creditworthiness or any information to be used for marketing purposes 30 days from the date that we first provided this notice if you have not opted-out.

**In order to revoke your consent for information sharing with Referral Partners and/or opt-out of Prosper affiliate information sharing, you may sign into your[Prosper Account](https://www.prosper.com/signin), select “Settings” from the drop down menu, and disable “Optional Information Sharing” in the section titled “Communication Preferences.” You may also contact us at [privacy@prosper.com](mailto:privacy@prosper.com) and we will assist you in disabling such information sharing**.

If you would like to exercise your right to opt-out of information sharing by a company affiliated with Prosper but not covered by this policy, you must consult that company’s privacy policy for instructions on how to exercise your right to opt-out of their information sharing.

* * *

**ADDITIONAL FACTS ABOUT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

**How you can change your personal information**

If you have an account, you can access the personal information you have provided to us by logging in to the “Settings” page of your account.  As a registered investor, you can update your password, email, phone number, or home address at any time.  As a registered borrower, you may update your password, email, phone number, bank account information or mailing address at any time, though certain changes prior to loan origination may require you to submit a new loan application. To change your information, you may also contact us at [support@prosper.com](mailto:support@prosper.com). We will respond to your request within a reasonable time.

We will retain your information for a minimum of seven years and as long as needed to provide you services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, conduct analysis, audits, or to enforce our agreements or as otherwise required by law.

**How Prosper Secures Your Information**

Prosper uses significant safeguards, including physical, technical (electronic), and operational controls to protect your personal information, both during transmission and once received. If you have any questions about the security of your information, you can contact us at [privacy@prosper.com](mailto:privacy@prosper.com).

Prosper equips all servers with an Extended Validation (EV) Secure Socket Layer (SSL) certificate to ensure that when you connect to our websites you can tell that you are actually on our site and that all data entered into the websites are transmitted to us in a secure encrypted channel. Once on our system, personal information can only be read or written through defined service access points, the use of which is password-protected. Data security is achieved through technical safeguards that include a combination of encryption, firewalls, intrusion detection system, malware detection system, and data loss prevention systems. Prosper also conducts vulnerability scans of applications and systems regularly.

Access to the system is tightly controlled and limited to only those who have a need to access information. Administrative safeguards such as a security awareness program, background checks, and internal information use policy ensure that only trained and trusted staff are permitted to access personal information. Some additional features of our security program include:

**_Secure Data Center_**

We store all sensitive financial information in state-of-the-art, highly secure data centers that are audited per SSAE 16 Type II and/or SOC 2 Type II standards. Physical access to the data centers is strictly controlled and we use the latest threat prevention technologies such as network and web application firewalls, VPN, antivirus, Web filtering and antispam technologies.

**_Session Time-Outs_**

We employ session time-outs to protect your account or application. You will be logged out of the site automatically after a specified period of inactivity. This time-out feature reduces the risk of others being able to access your account or information if you leave your computer unattended.

**_Passwords_**

If you have an account, at a minimum, we require the use of both numbers and letters in your password. We have also instituted secure steps by which you can regain access to your account should you forget your password. You should always choose a password that is difficult for others to guess and change your password frequently.

**Additional Steps You Should Take to Ensure the Security of Your Information**

Prosper sends important communications regarding your account or application via email. You should therefore take steps to secure and restrict access to your email account and change your email account password frequently. You should also be aware of fraudulent emails known as “phishing,” from companies claiming to be Prosper and requesting your login information or other account information. Prosper will never ask for your login information in an email.

When you are finished using our site, you should log out completely, then close the browser window and clear the browser’s cache files and saved passwords.  This step is particularly important if you use a computer that is accessed by other people, such as in a public library or Internet café.

**Changes to this policy**

Any updates to the privacy policy become effective when posted on the websites. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by email or by providing the revised privacy policy in your account on www.prosper.com. Your continued use of our services following the update means that you accept Prosper’s updated privacy policy.

For additional information, or if you have any questions regarding this policy or the privacy practices at Prosper, please submit your questions or comments directly to [privacy@prosper.com](mailto:privacy@prosper.com).

Note: Prosper Marketplace Inc. is the parent company of Prosper Funding LLC. Prosper Funding LLC owns the Prosper platform and website ([www.prosper.com](http://www.prosper.com/)) and application as well as loans underlying all borrower payment dependent notes. Prosper Marketplace, Inc. operates the Prosper platform and provides administrative support to Prosper Funding LLC.

You can also send questions or comments to:

Prosper Marketplace, Inc.  
Attn: Compliance Department  
221 Main Street, Suite 300  
San Francisco, CA 94105  
1-855-755-1919

* * *

Effective date: December 21, 2018

**Federal Privacy Notice** Rev. 12/2018

###### FACTS

###### WHAT DOES PROSPER DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?

###### Why?

Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do.

###### What?

The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you have with us. This information can include:

  * Social Security Number and income
  * Account balances and transaction history
  * Credit history, credit scores and employment information

When you are _no longer_ our customer, we continue to share your information as described in this notice

###### How?

All financial companies need to share customers’ personal information to run their everyday business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their customers’ personal information; the reasons Prosper chooses to share; and whether you can limit this sharing.

###### Reasons we can share your personal information

###### Does Prosper share?

###### Can you limit this sharing?

###### For our everyday business purposes—

such as to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, or report to credit bureaus

Yes

No

###### For our marketing purposes—

to offer our products and services to you

Yes

No

###### For joint marketing with other financial companies

No

We Don’t Share

###### For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes—

information about your transactions and experiences

Yes

No

###### For our affiliate’s everyday business purposes—

Information about your creditworthiness

Yes

Yes

###### For our affiliates to market to you 

Yes

Yes

###### For nonaffiliates to market to you 

Yes

Yes

###### To limit our sharing

You may limit our sharing of information by signing into your [Prosper Account](https://www.prosper.com/signin), selecting “Settings” from the drop down menu, and disabling “Optional Information Sharing” in the section titled “Communication Preferences.” You may also contact us at [privacy@prosper.com](mailto:privacy@prosper.com) and we will assist you in disabling such information sharing.

Following the instructions above will also revoke your consent provided in the above privacy policy for certain information sharing with nonaffiliated companies.

**Please note:**

If you are a new customer, we can begin sharing your information 30 days from the date we sent this notice (except where we have received your affirmative consent to begin sharing information sooner, through our privacy policy or otherwise). When you are no longer our customer, we continue to share your information as described in this notice. However, you can contact us at any time to limit our sharing.

##### Who we are

###### Who is providing this notice?

Prosper Funding LLC

Prosper Marketplace, Inc.

##### What we do

###### How does Prosper protect my personal information?

We protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use with security measures that comply with federal law. These measures include computer safeguards and secured files and building.

###### How does Prosper collect my personal information?

We collect your personal information, for example, when you

  * Open an account or apply for a loan
  * Provide us information including your income and employment information
  * Make a payment on your personal loan

We also collect your information from others, such as credit bureaus, affiliates, or other companies.

###### Why can’t I limit all sharing?

Federal law gives you the right to limit only

  * sharing for affiliates’ everyday business purposes—information about your creditworthiness
  * affiliates from using your information to market to you
  * sharing for nonaffiliates to market to you

State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing

###### What happens when I limit sharing for an account I hold jointly with someone else?

Your choices will apply to everyone on your account – unless you tell us otherwise.

##### Definitions

###### Affiliates

Companies related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and nonfinancial companies:

  * _In addition to the companies listed on this notice, our affiliates include BillGuard, Inc., BillGuard Technologies Ltd., and Prosper Assets Holding LLC._

###### Nonaffiliates

Companies not related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and nonfinancial companies.

  * _Nonaffiliated companies we share with include financial services companies, marketing companies, and other service providers._

###### Joint marketing

A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market financial products or services to you.

  * _Prosper doesn’t jointly market._

##### Other Important Information

**Telephone Communications:** Prosper and its authorized agents, service providers, originating banks and partners may monitor and/or record all telephone communications in accordance with applicable law.

**Vermont Residents:** We will not disclose information about your creditworthiness to our affiliates and will not disclose your personal information, financial information, credit report, or health information to nonaffiliated third parties to market to you, other than as permitted by Vermont law, unless you authorize us to make those disclosures.

**Nevada Residents:** We are providing you this notice pursuant to state law. You may be placed on our internal Do Not Call List by calling 855-755-1919 or emailing privacy@prosper.com. Nevada law also requires us to provide you with the following to obtain additional information: Bureau of Consumer Protection, Office of the Nevada Attorney General, 555 E. Washington Street, Suite 3900, Las Vegas, NV 89101; Phone: 702.486.3132; Email: BCPINFO@ag.state.nv.us.
